Everyone's John. So, today we're going
to go through probably the biggest
buzzwords in AI agent system recently,
agent harness, loop engineering, LLMOps,
which stands for large language models
operations, eval, which stands for
evaluation system for AI agents. And
these things become popular or become
viral on the internet not because they
are just some really complicated
concepts. Instead, they're actually very
simple. And I believe that simple
building blocks will actually help us
build the biggest architecture in the
world that will function like an
intelligent system. Let's walk through
this step-by-step, and it does not
matter if you're technical or not. We're
going to go through this and we'll make
sure that you're equipped with the right
knowledge for prompting your way through
building such a system in the future.
Let's jump in and get started. For those
of you who have watched my previous
video on AI agent memories, you're
probably already familiar with this
chart. This is an AI agent run, which
means that it takes an input from a user
prompt. For example, you're asking
ChatGPT or Deep Seek a question and say,
"Hey, when was Sam Altman fired from
OpenAI?" And then it's going to go
through entire run, but the end goal is
that you want to get a response. This is
actually ephemeral, which means that
there's no memory in this at all. We're
sending that question, "When was Sam
Altman fired?" and any chat history
that's currently in the chat. For
example, maybe we had some conversations
before that, which for example could be
you should talk to me like Elon Musk
grilling on Sam Altman because they
don't like each other. And then these
things will be fed into this thing
called a working memory or a context
RAM. In this video, we probably won't
dive too much in-depth into the memory
system because there's a previous video
talking about it already. I'll just
quickly go through it and then we'll
introduce the concept of what a harness
means. When you have these kind of
short-term working memory, there will be
an LLM or a large language model which
performs as a question and answer agent.
And at the end, you're going to get a
reply. But the problem with a simple
agent run with simply just the question,
current chat history, and system prompt
is that the memory is very short-term.
But when you run an AI agent system,
sometimes we need extra memories. For
example, how should the agent respond to
the person? A procedural memory is
exactly that. It basically tells the
agent how to act and what are some of
the instructions for the skill. We might
also want the agent to know some durable
facts about this context. For example, I
might want to compare my own early-stage
startup journey with Sam Altman's early
startup journey. We need this agent to
have a memory of who I am, which in this
context would be a durable facts or a
semantic memory. Who Sean is, what did
he build in the past? These kind of
things became a fact that you want your
agent to know, but they're not publicly
available if you're not famous because
the AI model won't be trained on such
information yet. But if you're famous
already, you can skip this. They already
know who you are. And another thing we
need is called episodic memory, and they
include things like the past events or
past chat history that does not exist in
this current conversation. For example,
I might suddenly be wondering, "When was
the last time I was preparing for a job
application?" And can we retrieve that
information and match, you know, if we
can get a job in ChatGPT. So, these
things will be retrieved from this thing
called an episodic memory, which is
basically a time series of the previous
conversations or previous triggers that
happened if you have a more complex
system. So, for those of you who have
watched my previous memory agent system
design, you might be wondering, "Sean,
why are you repeating all of these
things?" And that is because if you
think about the entire thing that we
just covered in the past few minutes,
we're really stating the one fact that a
large language model can't do these
things by itself. It's like a really
powerful brain that knows everything
about humanity, everything about
science, anything that happened in human
or biology history. But, it does not
know you. With you or the software who's
running this AI agent system, the large
language model has no clue with how you
want it to perform. This is why the
concept called harness becomes really
important in this. What harness means
literally is that it's a set of harness
tools that you use to control a horse
when you're doing a horse riding.
Imagine this large language model is a
horse, right? This horse is very
powerful, they can run around, but if
you don't have a good set of tools to
ride this horse, you could just get
hurt, you might go anywhere, you might
go somewhere random. If you're in a war,
you don't want that to happen. And
that's why we're doing all of these to
make sure we have good control over this
large language model and make sure we're
utilizing it at its maximum potential.
That's why in addition to just the
question or use a prompt and getting the
reply, and we're feeding them all in as
a working memory which can be enhanced
by these three memories we just talked
about. And in order for these three
memories to actually work, there's a bit
more details and they're all included in
Harness. Remember, Harness means we're
building this agent framework to control
this large language model so that it
works the way we want. For those of you
who study statistics or machine
learning, you would understand that a
large language model is actually
predicting the probability of the next
word that it should spit out. When
everything comes with probability,
there's randomness in it. But when we
solve problems, we sometimes don't want
too much randomness. So, that's why we
need to have a good control over this
technology. Now, let's continue to
finish this Harness. There are lots of
tools on the market that's already quite
useful. For example, you could try tools
like LangGraph, LangChain, or Pydantic,
and there are many others. In this
video, we won't dive too much in depth
into that, and we're going to finish
building up this Harness before we move
on to the next topic. So again, for this
agent to work properly, we need this
memory system to work, but this memory
system needs an update system cuz memory
doesn't just exist or pop up from
nowhere. You need to constantly update
it. That's why we need a database to
store all these memories so that when
the agent is running in this agent run,
it knows where to retrieve these
memories. So, whenever you see an icon
like this, this is a database, okay?
Procedural memory is basically remember
it's it's about instructions, right?
It's about how the agent should be
acting. It's like with a Harness on a
horse, you want the horse to ride faster
or slower. Normally, these are just
files or text, and that's why you
probably heard of this buzzword called
skills. Skill is basically a piece of
text in a markdown file that you feed
into AI agent like Clockwork. But, if
you want to harness the system well,
just having files and text is not
enough. And they're stored in databases
say like AWS, Superbase, Google Cloud,
you know, Azure, all these kind of
places. Or you can set up your own
server at home if you want, but that's
just too expensive. You don't want to do
that. And in order for this harness to
work properly, you also need to figure
out how to store the memories, okay? So,
for example, the episodic memory is a
time series of the events that happened
or the previous chat history, again. The
way we store it is actually very simple.
You just track every single thing that
happened, and then it's going to become
like a very long list of things that
happened in history with timestamps.
Durable facts is different story. You
can either input it yourself or you want
the system to sort of automatically
evolve over time. And the way for it to
evolve is that you want to consolidate
some of the conversations into the
semantic memory. If I'm running a D2C
brand e-commerce company, perhaps my
customers have talked to my customer
service agents for a million times about
how do I get reimbursed if this product
does not work? You want to consolidate
these conversations and distill them as
a fact into the semantic memory. And
that's why here we have a little gate
here. If a brand has a million people
purchasing products from it, let's say
you're Alibaba or Amazon, it just
doesn't make sense, and it's very
expensive. So, from a harness
perspective, you want to be smart about
this, and you want the system to be
automatic. And then simple way is
probably like maybe consolidate these
time-ordered events after every say
2,000 conversations because you have a
million customers. And then you can feed
these things into a summarizer agent,
which is another large language model
harness. You can define the system
prompt in this one. You can probably
feed it with some memories, too. Uh you
can configure different models. Maybe it
could be a cheaper model because you're
feeding too much text into it. So, the
context window's too big, and probably
these are very expensive. So, you can
use cheaper open-source models if you
want to. Having such a mechanism allows
you to consistently update this memory
system. The data should be coming from
the previous large language model
replies. Again, let's review how this
harness works. A user sent a prompt
where in one Asian runtime with the
current chat history and how the agent
should be performing, the system prompt,
we're preparing a working memory for
this AI agent to be able to answer a
question. And after every single time it
answered a question, it will send these
messages to this database. And then this
database is basically is feeding back to
this working memory every single time
when a question is checking for relevant
context. And at the same time, because
this database is too big, sometimes you
want to consolidate them into some
summarized information or distilled
facts so that they're stored properly in
a semantic memory so that the retrieval
of such memories is just faster. I know
we talked about retrieval a lot and
that's just another buzzword called rag,
which is retrieval augmented
generations. I also have a few videos
explaining what rags are. Feel free to
watch them. There's a little bit of
difference between how retrieve from
semantic memory and episodic memory. For
semantic memory, it's just rags because
these are just facts and text or files,
right? But then for episodic memory,
remember this is a time series. Let's
say we're still in this e-commerce
store, right? The user question could be
like, "What are the previous 10
conversations that we had with this
specific customer from the US?" And then
you might just need a SQL query to query
something that's pretty recent from this
episodic memory. But if your question is
like, "What were my previous 20
conversations that have customer
complaints on the quality of the
products and our agent did not
successfully resolve." With such a
question, you not only need a SQL query,
which is just capturing the dated events
in a data table, you also want to do
some semantic search. And that's why
here rag is important because it's
checking for relevant information for
you. You don't want the entire 2,000
messages. You want that 20 messages out
of these 2,000 that are exactly relevant
to what you want. And because these
complaints are in text, we need to do
some retrieval augmented generation to
match the semantic meanings between text
and the user prompt, so that you're
fetching the right context for the
working memory. By now, this is probably
a fast walk-through of the memory system
again, but we're just thinking about it
from a hardness perspective in this
video. And remember for harness, we're
training this horse of LLM to run
autonomously without having too much
randomness, okay? There's another piece
of it that's quite important, which is
the agent might not only just read the
memory. It might also do some tasks or
call some tools. When an agent calls
tools, it might not necessarily be just
one-time call. It could be multiple
times of calls. For instance, let's say
this AI agent has a bunch of agentic
tools such as help me schedule a
meeting, help me read or write my
customer relationship data from the CRM
system, or help me fetch the payment
information say from Stripe or Alipay.
And here's something we should be
careful about. If we give this horse or
this LLM technology full power, it could
just continuously do this forever,
right? Or it might not even know what's
the right time to stop or what is the
right tool calls it should make, when is
the end point to decide, okay, this
response is good enough, let's move on
to reply. That's why we have this
mechanism called end loop guardrails.
Yes, now we're talking about loop
engineering, one of the biggest
buzzwords in the recent few months. A
loop is part of harness. Why? Because a
loop is also helping us to control this
technology to make sure it runs the way
we want it to run. An example that could
be helpful for you is that let's say the
custom prompt is help me find out what
customers are complaining about our
products. What are some of the
follow-ups we could do in order to win
them back. And if they're asking for
reimbursement, have we done the
reimbursement or not? If not, can we do
that? This is probably a series of
questions, but sometimes we just dump
all of these things into AI agent, okay?
And after you have this prompt, this LLM
agent needs to decide, okay, what are
some of the tools that could be helpful
for me to finish this task? Loop here is
basically an architectural thinking of
when is good enough so that we stop and
give the user or the business owner a
reply, okay? So, what might happen here
is that the LLM agent is doing a bunch
of tool calls, it's doing some thinking,
it's saying, let me read from our
customer relationship management tool
like Salesforce, HubSpot, or Automanous.
And then it's going to find out, okay,
there were 30 customer complaints in the
past 2 months. 12 of them have got
reimbursement, the other eight have not
got reimbursement. So, after the first
initial fetch, it's probably responding
to the AI agent, right? And the agent
will be probably thinking, okay, the the
task or the ask is that can we can we
follow up with some of those who did not
get
the reimbursement, right? So, and then
it probably like just make another tool
calls and be like, hey, let's schedule a
meeting with those customers who did not
get a reimbursement, which are the eight
of them. If we go a little bit more
advanced, we even just use the
reimbursement trigger on Stripe or
Alipay to refund the customer. Can you
see that this is a loop until we finish
the task? And but of course, this is
like a case-by-case situation. It really
depends on what your task is, how you
build the system. So, there's no
one-solution-fits-all. Here, I'm just
explaining what a loop is. The very,
very essential part of this loop is that
it needs to know when it should stop.
That's why we need this end loop
guardrails. The guardrails could just
simply be the task is done. And perhaps
when the agent was doing the planning,
it should confirm with the user what is
a good ending point. It might clarify
with you, is this what you want,
reimbursing the other eight people, or
should I just tell you who they are and
then you will follow up later? All
right, these are two different decisions
you can make. And after you make, you're
basically telling the agent loop that
there's an ending scenario. Another good
example I saw today is that, you know,
when you're doing coding and cloud code
can just always pop up some windows and
ask you for permissions, right? So, the
good way to use a loop engineering here
is that you can set up a loop or set up
a hook in clock code and telling it that
you should always send me a notification
on my laptop if you are pending on some
permissions from me. Otherwise, if I'm
watching YouTube and then when I come
back 30 minutes later, I realize that
clock code is stuck in that one
permission like 25 minutes ago. That
would be a waste of my time, okay? So,
you can set up a loop like this to make
sure that there's a way to send you
notification pop-ups so that you know
the loop has ended or it needs your
input again. Are you guys still with me?
Good. So, by far we have covered AI
agent run with a memory system, with a
loop engineering around the large
language model agent, which has a
trigger to end the loop so that it sends
a reply to the user, and basically this
whole thing is an AI agent harness
system. What's next is one of the other
biggest buzzwords that Y Combinator
always mentions, which is eval or LLM
ops. Let's jump into it. But firstly, I
want you to understand why do we need
LLM ops here? Let's still look at the
left-hand side with this harness system.
The biggest problem here is that we
don't know how well it's performing. And
that's why we need a feedback loop to
help us understand is this agent
actually performing properly, right? For
my business or for my use case. And can
I continuously get feedback on how do we
fix it and actually fix it ourselves,
okay? And when we say fix it, a simple
way to understand it is that
can we have a better system prompt?
Can we have a better large language
model configurations?
Is there something we should change for
how we retrieve the AI agent memories?
These are kind of things that we can
continue to iterate. But in order to
iterate to make sure this system runs
properly, we need a way to evaluate it,
diagnose problems, solve the problems
until it's a healthy and well-performing
system. And that is called large
language model operations system, LLM
ops. So again, in order to understand
this properly, we need to come back to
what an agent run is. So an agent run,
you can simply understand it as a user
question is sent to a large language
model and then you get a reply. That is
one agent run. But in this agent run,
the agent tool calling could happen
multiple times. That does not matter,
right? We're just talking about from a
user input to a response from agent
perspective. That's one agent run. And
then we're going to introduce this
system called a tracing system. So every
agent run, we should trace like a tree
of events that happened. And there are
lots of tools that could help you with
that. It could be LangFuse, could be
LangSmith, etc., etc. A tree of events
could be like what did the person
actually ask, what retrievals did the
model actually retrieve, how many times
did the large language model actually
call the tools, and how was the tool
usage, how was the response time, right?
How long did it take for this entire
system to run for checking latencies,
and how many tokens have we used when we
do these tool calls, agent run, you
know, doing this retrieval augmented
generation, these kind of things. So
trace is helping us to track events,
basically. And that's the first step.
This is the step first to collect data.
And these data will be used for the
following two purposes. Was it a good
system run? And was it healthy? Which
corresponds to evaluation system.
We can probably use large language model
as a judge here to give us a score on
how well it performed. For example, if
the task has something to do with
schedule meetings, did the meeting
actually triggered? How long was the
response for an agent to reply to a
question? Was it 20 seconds or was it 2
milliseconds? And also things like how
many tokens have we used? These two are
basically in the same system. You can
write it as a deterministic code, you
can use an AI agent to do it, but this
is like part of the procedure, which is
helping us to understand was this a
healthy system?
And was it a good system? And after
that, we're going to diagnose, okay,
where and why something was broken. For
example, the meeting scheduling event
was never triggered. Why was that?
Right? We want to understand why was
that. And we could probably feed that
into coding agent in Claude to sort of
deep dive into it. Or, you know, if the
latency is 20 seconds instead of 2
milliseconds, something's wrong. Maybe
one of the tool call is taking too much
time.
Maybe the working memory is too large,
uh so that the response time for a large
language model to a memory retrieval is
just taking too much time. Maybe not
every single question requires a
retrieval from all these gigantic memory
system. Maybe you're just asking a
simple question be like, when was my
birthday? When was OpenAI started? And
these kind of information you probably
don't need to do a ton of retrieval. The
model itself already knows. So, you
basically want this system to provide a
dashboard for you to understand the
metrics. And then, with these metrics,
you can diagnose what is going wrong.
And then we're going to have a little
gate here, which is if the evaluation
system passed, well, you can define the
rules, we can either ship some very
simple fix, have a new version of the
prompt, or update the model
configuration, you know, some tool
changes, or the parameters for
retrievals. The LLM Ops will feed the
improved system prompt and the
configuration of the model back to this
agent run system. When then one LLM Ops
loop is finished. If, let's say,
something is deeply broken, right? We
cannot just simply ship the latest
version of the prompt. Then we should go
fix the bug, rerun the agent run, resend
the question, and then retrace the
events, and then redo this evaluation
system in this LLM Ops architecture. So,
now let's zoom out and look at this
chart one more time. We covered what an
AI agent run is, we covered how it would
retrieve information from memories, and
we understood how an LLM agent would ask
questions, would call tools to help it
finish the task in a loop, and it knows
when to stop the loop so that it we can
get the reply. This whole thing is a set
of harness tools that we're controlling
this horse, this technology, to run in
the right direction, okay, to do the
right task. And at the same time, we
have like a health checking system or
evaluation system to understand how
every single run is being traced, is
being observed, and how do we diagnose
some problems and fix some problems, and
ship the latest updates of the prompt,
about the model configuration, about all
these parameters or knobs that needs to
be updated, so that this system will be
an autonomous system that will just
self-evolve and grow over time. I really
hope this was helpful. Let me know what
you think, and if you have any
questions, you can always reach out to
me. I'll see you in the next video.
Thanks so much.